# SHIVDHWAJ PANDEY

305, Omkar Sai, Lower Parel, Mumbai | Mobile: +917387767716 | Email: shivdhwai@gmail.com | Website: https://shivdhwai.github.jo

# MIDDLE-LEVEL PROFESSIONAL: Over 8+ years of experience Application Development and Architect

## **Professional Summary**

The developer is involved in full-stack development and enhancing the already built system. Startup Experience in Applications Development life-cycle from the requirement to launch. Skilled in technical leadership, communication and presentations. Experienced in project lifecycle from design to implementation to integration and from recruitment of team to train for production-ready till delivery and maintenance.

### **Skills**

- Working experience in StartUp culture
- Worked in PHP, Node Js, Python
- E-commerce & Media background
- API design, development, software architect, microservices architect knowledge

## **Technologies Used:**

- Caching, Microservices, Amazon Web Services
- Mysql, Angular, Python, Mongo
- Laravel, Splinter, CakePHP, Bootstrap, Selenium, Sailsjs, ExpressJs, NodeJs, Python, Hapi Js, Core PHP

## **Work History**

- TickledMedia Mumbai
  - Senior Backend Developer 07/2019 to Current
- Stylabs Info Solutions Mumbai
  - OP/2017 to 06/2019
- Browntape Technologies Goa
  - Senior Software Developer 05/2016 to 07/2017
  - **Web Technologist** 04/2014 to 04/2016
- Codefire Technologies Noida, UP
  - o Junior Software Developer 06/2013 to 03/2014

- Designed and developed web applications, chrome extensions and maintained projects, worked as a full stack developer.
- Developed the products which cut time-consuming processes of E-commerce.
- Developed and designed the applications for Internal Teams and Mega Clients.
- Helped the Project Management team to fix the issue in the development cost.
- Scrapped data automation and migration of MySql to MongoDB in Hackathon.
- Won Best Fresher on Job Training and appreciation for a quick learner.

#### **Projects**

# Browntape (<a href="http://app.browntape.com/">http://app.browntape.com/</a>)

**Project description** - It handles day to day ac activity of E-commerce sellers for multiple marketplaces at a single place.

Tech Stack - CakePHP, Mysql, JS, Jquery, Bootstrap, APIs, Python, Splinter, Sphinx, Redis, Angular, Charts, Scraping

- •Worked on backend and frontend on various modules like Inventory, Price, Orders, Report, Dashboard (Sales Analytics).
- Refactoring of the code on performance tuning, Conversion of existing code into Angular or Python.
- Channel integration from top to bottom Order Flow, Order Processing, Inventory Management, Reporting, Pricing.
- Handled the REST, SOAP APIs as well as Scraping data from various sources.

# Picchamp (<a href="http://picchamp.browntape.com/">http://picchamp.browntape.com/</a>)

**Project description** - It helps to smoothen the E-commerce process in an easy and automated way to make life easy.

Tech Stack - Core PHP, Mysql, JS, Jquery, Bootstrap, APIs, Python

- •Designed and developed the application and led a team of 5 developers.
- •Created scrapers under this which helped sales and marketing teams to grab the e-commerce sellers from various places.

Adapter (http://adapter.browntape.com/)

**Project description** - It is for the middleware application between Browntape App and ERP Systems for Mega Clients.

Tech Stack - CakePHP, Mysql, JS, Jquery, Browntape APIs, Custom Logging, Crons, Python, Webhooks

- •Designed this application and developed in 10 days and released the beta version of this product with 2 clients live.
- •Worked on design flow and database architecture of the application which handles a huge amount of data via API calls via Crons.
- •Worked on backend and frontend and Managed the entire application.

## **BTAuth (Chrome Extension)**

Project description -It helps to organise the level of visibility of data to employees of browntape and their access.

Tech Stack - Core PHP, Mysql, JS, Jquery, Bootstrap, Google APIs

- •Worked on the design flow of the application and designed database architecture.
- · Backend coding and final release flow were developed.

# Sachmuch (http://sachmuch.com/)

**Project description** - It is a crowdfunding networking platform. Organizing occasions, raising funds, running web campaigns.

Tech Stack - CakePHP, Mysql, JS, Jquery, Bootstrap, Facebook, Linkedin, Twitter APIs

- •Worked on backend and front-end.
- •Worked on core modules and managed the database tables relation.
- Integration of UI and enhancement into the existing code for faster page loads.

## **Education**

**MCA**: Computer Applications, 2013, 76.11%, Vishveshwarya Institute of Engineering and Technology - Ghaziabad, UP **BCA**: Computer Application, 2010, 76.11%, University Department of Computer Application - Bhagalpur, Bihar

#### **Personal Information**

Date of Birth: 15th July 1987

Father's Name: Mr Arvind Kumar Pandey

• Mother's Name: Mrs Arti Pandey

Emergency Tel. Nos: 09934877132, 09993716844

## **Additional Information**

- Participated in various conferences, seminars and hackathons
- Learning system design architecture